Name: Manoj Madduri Mobile: +1 (573) 284-3429

Email: mmadduri838@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mmadduri838/

Summary:

A Motivated Software Developer master's graduate from Christian Brothers University with Four year of experience in software development. With excellent problem-solving and troubleshooting abilities, I am confident in my capacity to make a substantial contribution to the success of the company. My goal is to help the team achieve their goals by creating quality and reliable software solutions.

Work Experience:

Client: Cognier INC, Atlanta Software Developer Responsibilities: Jan 2023 - Present

- Produced and Consumed Microservices with Spring-Boot, Spring-Cloud-Netflix (Eureka Server, Zuul, Hystrix, Splunk), Spring (Core, Web) and Webservices REST/SOAP.
- Experience in using build/deploy tools such as Jenkins, Docker for Continuous Integration & Deployment for Microservices.
- Worked with authentication implementations such as OAuth2.
- Developed, debugged, integrated, and deployed applications using Eclipse (IDE) and used GIT as Version Control.
- Created Jenkins jobs for continuous integration and continuous delivery to AWS environment.
- Deployed Spring Boot based micro services as Docker containers using Amazon ECS container services.
- Involved in setting up the application to run on AWS environment on multiple EC2 instances.
- Hands on with API modeling languages and documentation using Swagger and Postman for testing webservice.
- Designed and developed the UI components using Angular, JSP, HTML, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax/jQuery,
- Handled Browser compatibility issues for different browsers related to CSS and HTML.
- Used CSS3 Borders and Query Menus as part of the UI navigation.
- Produced client-side validation through JavaScript and Ajax for asynchronous communication.
- Created interface to manage user menu using JS, Angular JS and ¡Query.
- Used Query event handling in UI pages to display list boxes and to handle validations.
- Developed front end interfaces and involved in Error Handling using JSP.
- Participated in peer reviews and code reviews for every sprint.
- Participated in the production deployment schedules.
- Audits and estimations for projects were done.
- Executed and programmed on an application development, helped team through all phases of the software development lifecycle.

Client: Keus Automation, India Software Developer Responsibilities: Jan 2018 - Jan 2021

- Contributed to the development lifecycle of enterprise applications for 3 year, engaging in Analysis, Design, Development, Implementation, and Testing.
- Reviewed code and debugged errors to improve performance.
- Applied HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, Redux, and JavaScript skills to create and enhance user

- interfaces in various projects.
- Utilized SQL for database development, including writing queries and crafting PL/SQL, NOSQL, Stored Procedures, and Triggers on the Oracle Database.
- Collaborated with technical teams to implement new technologies, incorporating React and Redux for enhanced functionality.
- Developed custom programs using JavaScript to build and configure solutions, as well as to generate comprehensive reports.
- Created high-level design documents, application interfaces, and detailed function/nonfunctional requirements.
- Applied Git for version control, ensuring efficient collaboration and code management.
- Implemented server-side logic, database interactions, and user authentication using PHP.
- Experience in using Emacs for code editing, navigation, and search functionalities.
- Successfully managed and manipulated files on Linux systems, demonstrating expertise in file permissions, ownership, and access control
- Collaborated in team-based, Agile environment to accomplish objectives by deadlines.

Technical Skills:

Java8, Java Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Micro services, AWS, Git Hub, Eureka Server, Zuul, Hystrix, Splunk, Docker, Git, Jenkins, IBM WebSphere, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, React, Redux, JavaScript, PL/SQL, NOSQL, Oracle Database, PHP, Linux, Agile, Jira, Maven, Eclipse, Angular, JSP, , EC2, OAuth2, Object Oriented Programing, IntelliJ, Code Review, Rest API, Data Structures & Algorithms.

Education:

Master's

Computer Information Systems

Aug 2021 – Dec 2022
Christian Brothers University, Memphis

GPA 3.54 4.0

Bachelor's-

Electrical and Electronics Engineering May 2014 – Sept 2017 NRI Institute of Technology

Strengths:

Commutation: Open-minded, outgoing, and patient in conversations with others. **Problem-Solving:** I always take my time to do research and think outside the box. **Flexibility/Organizational skills:** Able to work overtime to meet deadlines.